♪Don't feel sad for the fallen flowers♪
♪ لا تشعر بالحزن على الزهور الحزينة ♪
♪Falling in the mortal world♪
♪ يتظاهر في العالم الفاني ♪
♪Keep all the memories♪
♪ استمر في جميع الذكريات ♪
♪Can't find any peace anymore♪
♪ لا يمكن العثور على أي سلام بعد الآن ♪
♪The storms can't kill my passion♪
♪ العواصف لا يمكن أن تقتل حمايتي ♪
♪But I need to endure♪
♪ لكنني بحاجة إلى تحمل ♪
♪Be serious even though I'm naive♪
♪ كن جادا على الرغم من أنني ساذجة ♪
♪If this is the destined fate♪
♪ إذا كان هذا هو القدر المقدر ♪
♪Even if I'll be hurt♪
حتى ولو تأذيت ♪
♪I'll protect the people♪
♪ سأحمي الناس ♪
♪The mountains sun and moon can be my witnesses♪
♪ الجبال الشمس والقمر يمكن أن يكون شاهداي ♪
♪Full of passion♪
♪ مليء بالحماقة ♪
♪Deep love and hatred♪
♪ الحب والكراهية العميق ♪
♪Melts in my heart along with the snow♪
♪ يذوب في قلبي مع الثلج ♪
=Royal Rumours=
= الشائعات الملكية =
=Episode 17=
= الحلقة 17 =
Come in.
ادخل
Master Yun.
سيد يون
While you were recovering
بينما كنت تتعافى
at His Highness's place,
في مكان سموه
Qing Yue disappeared
اختفى تشينغ يويه
and
و
his belongings in his room
أمتعته في غرفته
were looted
تم نهبها
one night.
في ليلة واحدة
Master Yun.
سيد يون
It was my negligence,
كان إهمالي
please punish me.
أرجوك عاقبني
It's not your fault.
هذا ليس خطأك
Master Yun.
سيد يون
When will you be back?
متى ستعودين؟
I'm almost healed.
كدت أشفى
I'll be back tonight.
سأعود الليلة
You may leave.
يمكنك المغادرة
Yes, Master Yun.
نعم، سيد يون
(Who could be behind)
(من يمكن أن يكون وراء)
(Qing Yue's disappearance?)
(اختفاء تشينغ يويه؟)
(And who took all the things)
(ومن أخذ كل الأشياء)
(from his room?)
(من غرفته؟)
(If it was His Highness,)
(إذا كان سموه)
(why didn't he just ask me?)
(لماذا لم يسألني فقط؟)
(But if it was master,)
(ولكن إذا كان سيدنا،)
(why did he stay put?)
(لماذا بقي في مكانه؟)
(The Capital)
(العاصمة)
Move.
تحرك
Make way.
ابتعد
Get out of the way.
ابتعد عن الطريق
Move.
افسح الطريق
- Who is that princess? - Move.
- من تلك الأميرة؟ - تحرك - تحرك
- She's a show-off. - Make way.
- إنها محادثة... - إنها محادثة - افسح الطريق
Even our royal family
حتى عائلتنا المالكة
- are not as arrogant as this. - Move.
- ليست متعجرفة مثل هذا - تحرك
- Maybe
- ربما
- she's a princess from another state. - Make way.
- إنها أميرة من مقاطعة أخرى - افسح المجال
- We shouldn't bother - Move.
- لا ينبغي أن نتكبد العناء - تحرك
with these
مع هذه
- ignorant petty states. - Get out of the way.
- المقاطعات التافهة الجاهلة - ابتعدي عن الطريق
Hold on.
انتظر
They are wearing
إنهم يرتدون نفس الزي
the same outfit as us.
الملابس ذاتها مثلنا
You're right.
أنت على حق
How dare you insult our princess!
كيف تجرئين على إهانة أميرتنا!
Little girl.
فتاة صغيرة
Mind your own business.
اهتم بشؤونك الخاصة
Do you know
هل تعرف
who is inside the carriage?
من داخل العربة؟
I don't know.
لا أعرف
All I know is that
كل ما أعرفه هو أن
the States Assembly is coming
أن جمعية المقاطعات قادمة
and no one shall oppress the people.
ولا يجوز لأحد قمع الشعب
What's going on?
ماذا يجري؟
(Princess Le Yang)
(الأميرة لي يانغ)
This is ridiculous.
هذه سخيفة
Who is so bold
من الجريء جدا
to block my way?
لمنع طريقي؟
I am a marshal under the command of Marquis Chang'an.
أنا مستيري تحت قيادة ماركيز تشانغ آن
I'm in charge of
أنا مسؤولة
the States Assembly with Princess Hua.
جمعية المقاطعات مع الأميرة هوا
It's my duty to maintain order.
من واجبي الحفاظ على النظام
Who does Wei Mingyue think she is?
من تعتقد أنها هكذا؟
This is the capital,
هذه هي العاصمة
not Qinghan Prefecture.
وليس مقاطعة تشينغهان
You...
أنت...
Drive her away.
ادعها بعيدا
Don't go soft.
لا تنجو
Yes.
نعم
What is the penalty for
ما هي العقوبة على
assaulting people in the street?
الاعتداء على الناس في الشارع؟
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
Offenders to remove their trousers
الجناة لإزالة بنطالهم
and be publicly flogged ten times.
وجلدهم علنا عشر مرات
In serious cases, they will be sent to the border
في الحالات الخطيرة، يتم إرسالها سيتم إرسالهم إلى الحدود
to serve hard labour for five years.
لخدمة الأشغال الشاقة لمدة خمس سنوات
Take him down
انزل منه
and send him to the capital
وإرساله إلى العاصمة
for flogging.
للجلد
Let him learn
دعه يتعلم
the laws of our state.
قوانين مقاطعتنا
Who on earth are you?
من أنت يا ترى؟
Beat them.
اضربهم
Yes.
نعم
How dare you defy me!
كيف تجرؤ على تحديدي!
Guards.
حراس
Go!
اذهبي!
His Highness has arrived.
لقد وصل سموه
Aunt Le Yang.
عمتي لي يانغ
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
I haven't seen you for a year.
لم أرك منذ عام
You're a lot more handsome now.
أنت أكثر وسامة بكثير الآن
Your men
رجالك
don't seem to know the laws of this state.
لا يبدو أنهم يعرفون في هذه المقاطعة
So I'll send them to
لذلك سأرسلهم
learn about it at the palace.
لنتعرف على ذلك في القصر
You don't mind, right?
أنت لا تمانع، أليس كذلك؟
I am grateful to you
أنا ممتن لك
if you are willing to
إذا كان على استعداد
help me educate
لمساعدتي في تثقيف
my unruly servants.
خدماتي الجامحون
Didn't my daughter say
ألم تقل ابنتي
she wanted to see His Highness?
أرادت رؤية سموه؟
Go and get her.
اذهب وأحضرها
(Why do I feel like someone is)
(لماذا أشعر أن أحدهم هو)
(staring at me?) She should greet His Highness.
(تحدق بي؟) يجب أن تحية لسموه
Yes.
نعم
(Xie Yao)
(شي ياو)
(is indeed a beauty.)
(هي بالفعل جميلة)
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
(Prince Consort Xie's daughter, Xie Yao) It's been a while.
(ابنة الأمير القرين، شي ياو) لم أرك منذ وقت طويل
(Yaoyao?)
(ياو؟)
Nice to see you again.
سُررت لرؤيتك مرة أخرى
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
It's our bad.
انها سيئة
We've been away for so long
لقد كنا مختلفين لفترة طويلة
and we're unfamiliar with the capital.
ونحن غير مطلعين على العاصمة
That's why
لهذا السبب
we accidentally upset
أننا انزعجنا
those two big sisters.
هاتين الأختين الأكبر
(Who is your big sister?)
(من أختك الكبرى؟)
They blocked our way.
سمحوا لنا
Your Highness.
سموك
When did the capital
متى أصبحت العاصمة
become so formidable?
أصبحت هائلة جدا؟
Wait.
انتظر
What did you say?
ماذا قلت؟
Big sister?
أختي الكبيرة؟
Who were you talking about?
عمّن كنت تتحدثين؟
I was referring to
كنت أشير
the two big sisters next to you.
الأختين الأكبر بجانبك
They are younger than you.
هما أصغر منك
Don't get it wrong.
لا تسئ الفهم
If there's anything
إذا كان هناك أي شيء
I've done wrong,
فقد ارتكبت خطأ
please tell me.
من فضلك قل لي
I don't want you
لا أريدك
and His Highness to get the wrong idea.
وسموه أن يفكر بسوء الفهم
(How dare she steal my lines!)
(كيف تجرؤ على سرقة جدولي!)
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
So you and His Highness
لذلك أنت وصاحب السمو
are old acquaintances.
معارف قديمة
I can't believe
أنا لا يمكنني تصديق
you take me for
تأخذين علي
such a small-minded person.
مثل هذا الشخص ضيق الأفق
Yes,
نعم
His Highness and I
أنا وصاحب السمو
are indeed old acquaintances,
هما بالفعل معارفان قديمان
but since my sister's death,
ولكن منذ وفاة أختي
I've rarely had the chance
لم تتح لي الفرصة
to see His Highness.
لرؤية سموه
Your Highness.
سموك
Would you
هل تريد
like to show me
لأر
around the capital?
حول العاصمة؟
Sorry.
آسف
I don't have the time.
ليس لدي الوقت
I need to send Princess Hua home.
أحتاج إلى إرسال الأميرة هوا إلى المنزل
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
Let's go.
لنذهب
That girl just now
تلك الفتاة الآن
turns out to be Wei Mingyue's daughter.
اتضح أنها ابنة وي مينغيويه
That dumb Wei Mingyue
تلك الحمقاء وي مينغيويه
has raised
قام بتربية
a rude daughter.
ابنة وقحة
Mother, calm down.
أمي، اهدئي
You are good for nothing.
أنت خير من لا شيء
If it was your big sister...
إذا كانت أختك الكبرى
Now that you have a rival,
بما أن لديك منافس الآن
you must try to win His Highness's heart,
يجب أن تحاول الفوز بقلب سموه
you understand?
هل تفهمين؟
Yes, mother.
نعم، أمي
I've just returned.
لقد عدت للتو
So the Empress Dowager
إذًا إمبراطورة الأرملة
will give me some dignity.
سوف تعطيني بعض الكرامة
I'll give you another chance.
سأعطيك فرصة أخرى
Do you hear me?
هل تسمعينني؟
Yes, mother.
نعم، أمي
(Blossoming Wealth)
(الثروة المزدهرة)
(Hua Mansion)
(طائفة هوا)
Your Highness.
سموك
You are so kind.
أنت لطيفة جدا
How so?
كيف ذلك؟
You are not biased toward Lady Xie.
أنت لست متحيزة ضد السيدة شي
I am very happy.
أنا سعيد جدا
Why should I be partial to her?
لماذا يجب أن أكون منحازة إليها؟
You are my person.
أنت شخصيتي
Why don't you sit over at my house?
لماذا لا تجلسين في منزلي؟
Didn't you say
ألم تقولي
you liked the environment of my home?
كنت تحبين بيئة منزلي؟
But when I think of General Hua...
ولكن عندما أفكر في الجنرال هوا
I am not good at drinking.
أنا لست جيدا في الشرب
I'm afraid your parents
أخشى والديك
will find it inconvenient.
سوف يجدان الأمر غير ملائم
They won't.
لن يفعلوا
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Honey.
عزيزي
(Hua Mansion)
(طائفة هوا)
General Hua.
الجنرال هوا
General Wei.
الجنرال وي
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
It is indeed inconvenient.
هذا غير ملائم بالفعل
Changkong is preparing for his exam.
تشانغكونغ يستعد للامتحان
He really needs
إنه حقا بحاجة
some peace and quiet.
بعض السلام والهدوء
So we can't
لذلك لا يمكننا
entertain you today.
استمتعك اليوم
You are right.
أنت على حق
Then I'll leave first.
إذن سأغادر أولًا
Stop looking.
توقف عن البحث
(Hua Mansion)
(طائفة هوا)
Mother.
أمي
I was the one who invited
كنت أدعو سموه
His Highness to our home.
الأمير إلى منزلنا
Wasn't it a bit too rude of you
ألم يكن مجرد وقحة منك
to turn him down like that?
أن يرفضه هكذا
I've been thinking about it
كنت أفكر في الأمر
over the past two days.
على مدى اليومين الماضيين
His Highness
صاحب السمو
is really a nice guy.
هو حقا رجل لطيف
Liuli.
ليولي
Come with me.
تعالي معي
Go ahead.
اذهبي
You didn't learn your father's strengths,
لم تتعلم نقاط قوة والدك
instead, you picked up
بدلا من ذلك، أجبت
all the tricks he used
كل الحيل التي استخدمها
to please people.
لإرضاء الناس
I didn't.
أنا لم أستطع
Are you sure?
هل أنت متأكدة؟
Did you please His Highness
هل أرجوك سموه
because you like him?
لأنك مُعجبة به؟
Mother, what are you talking about?
أمي، عمّ تتحدث؟
Liuli.
ليولي
Look at me.
انظري إليّ
Let me ask you.
دعني أسألك
Do you see him
هل ترينه
as a man
كرجل
or a friend?
أو صديقة؟
Mother, stop it.
أمي، توقفي
Let's talk about something else.
دعنا نتحدث عن شيء آخر
I was too busy
كان مشغول جدا
with the war
بالحرب
and neglected to interact with you.
وإهمال التفاعل معك
I have a question for you
لدي سؤال لك
and I want you to answer me properly.
وأريد أن تجيبني بشكل صحيح
If your brother
إذا كان أخوك
was with another woman,
كان مع امرأة أخرى
would you be angry?
هل ستغضبين؟
Why would I?
لماذا؟
However,
لكن
I will see if that woman
سأرى إذا كانت تلك المرأة
qualifies to be my sister-in-law.
تستحق أن تكون شقيقة زوجي
But what if
ولكن ماذا لو
His Highness
سموه
was with another woman?
كان مع امرأة أخرى؟
No way.
لا يمكن
Then that woman
إذن تلك المرأة
will end up like this walnut.
سوف ينتهي بها المطاف هكذا المشي
Liuli.
ليولي
You are ambitious.
أنت طموحة
What do you mean?
ماذا تعني؟
Besides being a renowned
إلى جانب كونك مشهورة
delicate woman,
امرأة دقيقة
do you want to be the mother of a nation?
هل تريد أن تكون أم أمة؟
Mother.
أمي
A future Empress?
إمبراطورة مستقبلية؟
I'm not that capable.
أنا لست قادرا على ذلك
Then you have to remember one thing.
إذن يجب أن تتذكر شيئا واحدا
If His Highness
إذا كان سموه
does not confess his feelings first,
لا يعترف بمشاعره أولا
you must not reveal yours to him
يجب ألا تكشف عن مشاعرك له
in advance.
مقدما
He is the Crown Prince after all.
إنه ولي عهد في النهاية
I don't understand.
أنا لا أفهم
What do you mean by confessing?
ماذا تعني بالاعتراف؟
A smile and excitement that can't be concealed.
و لا يمكن إخفاء ذلك
Uncontrollable gestures.
إشارات لا يمكن السيطرة عليها
Irresistible affection.
مشاعر لا مقاومة لها
I see.
فهمت
Liuli.
ليولي
I wish I could
أتمنى لو أستطيع
let you go
دعك تذهب
and pursue your love,
ومتابعة حبك
but it's not that easy
لكن الأمر ليس بتلك السهولة
to start a family.
إنشاء عائلة
(Ceremonial Hall)
(قاعة الاحتفالات)
Greetings, ministers.
تحياتي يا وزراء
Greetings, Princess Hua.
تحياتي، الأميرة هوا
Today,
اليوم
we will learn some etiquette.
سنعرف بعض آداب السلوك
First,
أولا
Luoxia's cheek-to-cheek greeting.
تحية لوكسيا من شيك إلى شيك
Turn your body towards each other,
وجه جسدك نحو بعضها البعض
extend your arms,
امد ذراعيك
hold each other tightly,
تمسكا بعضكما البعض بإحكام
look into each other's eyes
انظرا إلى عيون بعضنا البعض
and keep smiling.
و يبتسم باستمرار
Greet.
تحية
Next one is
التالي هو
Zhi's handshake.
مصافحة تشي
Face each other.
وجه بعضنا البعض
The host must reach out
يجب أن يتصل المضيف
to the guest first.
إلى الضيف أولا
Pay attention to the strength.
اعتني بالقوة
Men can be gentle with women.
يمكن للرجال أن يكونوا لطيفين مع النساء
Don't shake the whole hand.
لا تتهز يدك بأكملها
Just the tips of the fingers.
أصابع الاتهام فقط
Keep smiling and bow.
و البتسم والقوس
Try it.
جربه
Yes.
نعم
It's fine.
لا بأس
I am not that fragile.
أنا لست هشة إلى تلك الدرجة
I don't need support.
لست بحاجة إلى الدعم
I can come down by myself.
يمكنني النزول بنفسي
Your Highness.
سموك
The western suburb is surprisingly crowded.
الضاحية الغربية هي مزدحمة بشكل مفاجئ
Thank you
شكرا لك
for bringing me here today
على إحضاري إلى هنا اليوم
for a walk.
لمرافقة
It wasn't my intention.
لم أكن أنوي ذلك
It was actually father's and grandmother's orders.
في الحقيقة وأوامر الجدة
I had to comply with them.
كان علي الامتثال لها
Lady Xie.
السيدة شي
Don't take it to heart.
لا تأخذ الأمر على محمل الجد
Hold each other's hand.
أمسك كل منا بيد الآخر
Look at each other.
انظرا إلى بعضكما
Keep smiling.
استمري في الابتسام
Don't hold the whole hand.
لا تمسكي بيد كاملة
Just the tips of the fingers.
مجرد نصيحة من أصابع اليدين
That's it.
هذه هي
Be mindful of the distance.
خذ في الحسبان المسافة
Don't hit your head.
لا تضرب رأسك
Miss.
الآنسة
His Highness is taking Lady Xie
سموه يأخذ السيدة شي
out for a stroll.
لتجول في الخارج
(I'm working here)
(أعمل هنا)
(and you're out there having a good time.)
(و) أنت في الخارج استمتعي بوقتك)
So pretty.
جميلة جدًا
Grow old together?
يكبر في السن معا؟
(Hua Mansion)
(طائفة هوا)
(I wonder what Liuli is doing now.)
(أتساءل ما الذي يفعله ليولي الآن)
It smells good.
رائحته جيدة
(Her carriage is not here.)
(عربتها ليست هنا)
(She's probably working at the Ceremonial Hall.)
(ربما تعمل في قاعة الاحتفالات) في قاعة الاحتفالات
Delicious.
لذيذ
Your Highness.
سموك
This is very delicious.
هذا لذيذ جدا
Try it.
جربي
What is this?
ما هذا؟
Your Highness.
سموك
This is a rabbit skewer.
هذا بانقطاع الأرانب
It is made from rabbit meat,
يُصنع من لحم الأرانب
infused with wine, sauce
مغطى بالنبيذ والصلصة
peppercorns
الفلفل
and then scalded with hot water.
ثم وسع نطاقه بالماء الساخن
It tastes delicious.
طعمه شهي
Rabbit meat?
لحم الأرنب؟
Why didn't you say it earlier?
لماذا لم تقولها من قبل
I...
أنا...
(She was gentle a moment ago.)
"كانت لطيفة قبل قليل"
Rabbit meat is good.
لحم الأرانب جيد
It's fresh.
إنه طازج
- (She's a totally different person.) - I really like
- (إنها شخص مختلف تمامًا) - أحب حقا
this unique flavour.
هذه النكهة الفريدة
I see.
فهمت
You only have a few customers.
لديك فقط عدد قليل من الزبائن
Is it because they're afraid to eat this?
هل هذا لأنهم هل تخشين تناول هذا؟
No.
لا
Hasn't Princess Hua
ألم تكن الأميرة هوا
ever considered
نظرت في
your subsistence?
الكفاف الخاص بك؟
Your Highness.
سموك
Your Highness, please forgive me.
صاحب السمو، أرجوك سامحني
For people like us,
أشخاص مثلنا
who have no skills,
الذين لا يملكون مهارات
harvesting and hunting
الحصاد والصيد
are how we make a living.
هي الطريقة التي نعيش بها
Princess Hua gave us
أعطتنا الأميرة هوا
the recipe for rabbit skewers
وصفة لبائعي الأرانب
so that we could
حتى نتمكن من
run a stall here
على أي حال
and finally
وأخيرا
earn a living.
كسبت رزقًا
She gave you the recipe,
أعطاك الوصفة
but didn't she consider
لكن ألم تنظر
the fact that no one would dare to eat it?
حقيقة أنه لا أحد هل يجرؤ على تناولها؟
(She's picking on me.) I...
(إنها تأكلي) أنا...
No.
لا
My business is doing well.
عملي على ما يرام
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
Enough. Please rise.
كفي، انهض
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
You did very well.
أبليت بلاء حسنًا
The western suburb was originally a deserted area,
كانت الضاحية الغربية في الأصل منطقة مهجورة
but it was only through the initiative of Princess Hua
لكنها لم تكن إلا من خلال من خلال مبادرة الأميرة هوا
that it came to be
أنها أصبحت حيوية كما هي اليوم
as lively as it is today.
بنشاط كما هو اليوم
This site is closely linked to Longjing Street.
هذا الموقع وثيق مرتبط بشارع لونغجينغ
After the States Assembly,
بعد جمعية المقاطعات
you needn't worry
لا داعي للقلق
about making a living.
على العيش
Thank you, Your Highness.
شكرا لك يا صاحب السمو
I am very grateful.
أنا ممتن جدا
(Men are worthless.)
(الرجال لا قيمة لهم)
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
Where are you going?
إلى أين أنت ذاهب؟
Lady Xie.
السيدة شي
I've already walked you
لقد شركتك بالفعل
down the street.
انزل في الشارع
Qi, Ba.
تشي، با
- Yes.
- نعم
If Lady Xie wants to go anywhere else,
إذا كانت السيدة شي تريد الذهاب إلى أي مكان آخر
go with her.
اذهب معها
- Yes.
- نعم
- Your Highness. - Lady Xie.
- صاحب السمو - السيدة شي
- There's a nice stall over there. - Yes.
- هناك كشك لطيف هناك - نعم
- You will like it. - Lady Xie, please.
- سوف يعجبك ذلك - السيدة شي، من فضلك - سيدة شي
Liuli.
ليولي
Mister.
سيدي
Bring me mature vinegar, rice vinegar, white vinegar, balsamic vinegar,
أحضر لي الخنزير الناضج، خنزير الأرز الخنزير الأبيض وخنزير البلسميك
all of them.
جميعها
Sure.
بالطبع
Then you have to remember one thing.
إذن عليك أن تتذكر شيئا واحدا
If His Highness
إذا كان سموه
does not confess his feelings first,
لا يعترف بمشاعره أولا
you must not reveal yours to him
يجب ألا تكشف عن مشاعرك له
in advance.
مقدما
He is the Crown Prince after all.
إنه ولي عهد في النهاية
(Vinegar)
(الخلّ)
I heard that
سمعت أنك
you were busy at the Ceremonial Hall.
كنت مشغول في قاعة الاحتفالات
Why are you back?
لماذا عدت؟
I want to drink vinegar.
أريد أن أشرب الخلّ
So sour.
حار جدا
Yuan Wei.
يوان وي
They all said that
قالوا جميعا إن
His Majesty is going to betroth
جلالة الإمبراطور سيخطب
Lady Xie to you.
السيدة شي بالنسبة لك
How come I didn't know?
كيف لم أكن أعرف؟
Your Majesty, drink slowly.
صاحب الجلالة، اشرب ببطء
Father.
أبي
You have to help me this time.
عليك أن تساعدني هذه المرة
What's the matter?
ما الأمر؟
I suddenly realised that
أدركت فجأةً أنني
I am a beast.
أنا وحش
Did you assault a woman?
هل هاجمت امرأة؟
Is that
هل هذا
what I am to you?
ما أكون بالنسبة لك؟
No.
لا
My son is talented
ابني موهوب
and good-looking.
وحسن المظهر
He would never do such an unlawful thing.
لن يفعل أبدا مثل هذا الشيء غير القانوني
So don't ever try to betroth
لذلك لا تحاول أبدا محاولة الخطوبة
Princess Le Yang's daughter,
ابنة الأميرة لي يانغ
Lady Xie,
السيدة شي
to me anymore.
بالنسبة إليّ بعد الآن
I have no feelings for her.
لا أكنّ لها المشاعر
San Cai.
سان باي
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم، صاحب الجلالة
Did I ever say that?
هل قلت ذلك من قبل؟
Your Majesty,
صاحبة الجلالة
you did mention it before.
لقد ذكرت ذلك من قبل
Then tell me.
إذن أخبرني
Who do you like?
من الذي تحب؟
Well...
إذن
I...
أنا...
Why are you stammering?
لماذا تختم؟
Just tell me.
أخبرني فحسب
Who do you like?
من الذي تحب؟
You know her.
أنت تعرفها
Who?
من؟
Hua Liuli.
هوا ليولي
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
لماذا لم تخبرني في وقت سابق؟
I almost
كدت
betrothed her to your brother.
خطبها لأخيك
So how far have you
إلى أي مدى وصلت؟
progressed?
تقدم؟
I think
أعتقد
she likes me as well.
إنها تحبني أيضا
She was even jealous of
حتى أنها كانت غيورة
Lady Xie today.
السيدة شي اليوم
Then have you ever
إذن هل سبق لك
confessed your feelings to her?
اعترفت لها بمشاعرك؟
Not yet.
ليس بعد
It seems you are not committed to her.
يبدو أنك لست ملتزما بها
I think
أعتقد
you'd better marry Xie Yao.
من الأفضل أن تتزوج شي ياو
No.
لا
Father.
أبي
That Xie Yao
أن شي ياو
is so pretentious.
هي مدبرة جدا
One minute she's soft,
في دقيقة واحدة هي ناعمة
one minute she's sobbing,
في دقيقة واحدة هي تسكع
the next she's acting cute.
تتصرف بظرافة في المرة التالية
My head hurts
رأسي يؤلمني
when I hear her talk.
عندما أسمع صوتها
Why do I feel that
لماذا أشعر أنك
you are talking about Hua Liuli?
هل تتحدث عن هوا ليولي؟
Father.
أيها الأب
You can't say that about Liuli.
لا يمكنك قول ذلك عن ليولي
Tell me.
أخبريني
How can I help you?
كيف يمكنني مساعدتك؟
Just don't randomly arrange a marriage for me.
فقط لا غير عشوائية قم بترتيب زواج لي
(Graceful House)
(بيت رشيق)
Miss.
الآنسة
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
His Majesty has sent
وقد أرسل جلالة الإمبراطور
several physicians to examine him.
العديد من الأطباء لفحصه
Grand Preceptor Du will be fine.
المعلم الكبير دو سيكون بخير
I still need to study medical books.
ما زلت بحاجة إلى دراسة الكتب الطبية
Maybe I can help with
ربما يمكنني المساعدة
grandfather's illness.
مرض الجد
(I wonder why Young Master Yun)
(أتساءل لماذا السيد يون)
(came to see me at this time.)
(جاء لرؤيتي في هذا الوقت)
Cai Wei.
باي وي
Get me a basin of water.
أحضري لي حوض ماء
Yes, Miss.
نعم يا آنسة
How are you, Lady Du?
كيف حالك يا سيدة دو؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير
Young Master Yun.
السيد يون
How is your wound healing?
كيف يتعافى جرحك؟
It has recovered,
لقد تعافى
thanks to your help
بفضل مساعدتك
in those few days.
في تلك الأيام القليلة
This is a thank-you gift.
هذه هدية شكر لك
Please accept it.
أرجوكم اقبلوها
I heard that Grand Preceptor Du
سمعت أن المعلم الكبير دو
had been in poor health recently.
كان في صحة سيئة مؤخرا
So I chose a picture of a pine tree,
لذلك اخترت صورة لشجرة الصنوبر
in hope it will bring good luck.
على أمل أنها ستجلب حظا جيدا
Thank you, Young Master Yun.
شكرًا لك يا سيد يون
(Chen Daoxi)
(تشن داوكسي)
This is Master Chen's handwriting.
هذا هو خط يد السيد تشن
This is too valuable.
هذا قيم جدا
I can't take it.
لا يمكنني أخذها
I don't appreciate it
أنا لا أقدر ذلك
even if it were in my place.
حتى لو كان في مكانه
You should keep it.
يجب أن تحتفظ به
Thank you, Young Master Yun.
شكرا لك يا سيد يون
You can
يمكنك
see the other one after I leave.
انظر الآخر بعد أن أغادر
I'll take my leave then.
سأغادر إذن
Your Highness.
صاحبة السمو
If my guess is correct,
إذا كان تخميني صحيحا
this is the poison Qing Yue used
هذا هو السم الذي استخدمه تشينغ يويه
to control Yun Han.
للسيطرة على يون هان
Qing Yue
تشينغ يويه
was doing his master's
كان يفعل معلمه
dirty work.
عمله القذر
Now that he is dead,
بما أن الآن مات
the man cut off
قطع الرجل
his contact with Yun Han directly.
الاتصال مع يون هان مباشرة
At least Yun Han is safe for the time being.
يون هان على الأقل آمن في الوقت الحالي
Are you sure?
هل أنت متأكدة؟
Your Highness.
سموك
Now that we've
الآن بعد أن
gotten this far.
وصلنا إلى هذا الحد
We just need to uncover one more lead
نحن فقط بحاجة إلى الكشف عن قيادة أخرى
and we will
وسنقوم
wipe them out.
للقضاء عليهم
We have to ask Yun Han face-to-face.
علينا أن نطلب من يون هان وجها لوجه
If I were to do that,
إذا كنت سأفعل ذلك
it would be no different from
لا يكون مختلفا
controlling someone with poison.
السيطرة على شخص ما بالسم
Then Yun Han...
إذن يون هان
Jihuai.
جيهواي
I don't want to be
لا أريد أن أكون
the one who pushes him off the cliff.
الشخص الذي يدفعه من الهاوية
I want to save him,
أريد أن أنقذه
not force him.
لا أجبره
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو
But you are also
لكنك أيضا
on the edge of a cliff.
على حافة الهاوية
You are wrong.
أنت على خطأ
I gave my trust to Yun Han
أعطيت ثقتي إلى يون هان
because we are in the open.
لأننا في العراء
That being the case,
ونظرا لأن هذا هو الحال
I'll take the risk.
سأتحمل المخاطرة
Your Highness.
سموك
You may leave.
يمكنك المغادرة
Yes, Your Highness.
نعم يا صاحب السمو
(Yun Han.)
(يون هان)
(How could you)
(كيف يمكنك)
(betray His Highness?)
(خيانة الأمير؟)
(Dafu Jewelry)
(جبل دافو)
If you see something you like, tell me.
إذا رأيت شيئًا يعجبك، أخبرني
I'll buy it for you.
سأشتريه لك
Mother.
أمي
Didn't you tell me to spend wisely?
ألم تطلبي مني أن أنفق بحكمة؟
Fortune is not
الحظ ليس
a substitute for happiness.
بديلة عن السعادة
I'm happy these days.
أنا سعيدة هذه الأيام
I know.
أعرف
It's because of Princess Le Yang,
إنه بسبب الأميرة لو يانغ
isn't it?
أليس كذلك؟
She's used to being arrogant and domineering.
لقد اعتادت أن تكون متعجرف متعجرف وسلطان
Now someone
الآن شخص ما
can finally confront her.
يمكن أن تواجهها أخيرا
Liuli is such
ليولي هكذا
a nice lady.
سيدة لطيفة
She has
لديها
the flair of General Wei in her day.
ذوق الجنرال وي في يومها
You need to hang out with her more.
يجب أن تقضي الوقت معها أكثر
Pick a few pieces of jewelry for her, too.
اختاري بعض القطع من المجوهرات عليها أيضا
But it's expensive.
لكنها باهظة الثمن
Then pick fewer for yourself
إذن اختاري أقل لنفسك
and buy more for her.
واشتر المزيد لها
This is not bad.
هذا ليس سيئا
This phoenix hairpin
دبوس الشعر هذا العنقاء
is mine.
هو لي
I thought it was someone else.
اعتقدت أنه كان شخصا آخر
So it's you, Le Yang.
إذًا هو أنت يا لي يانغ
You just grab others' stuff
أمسك بأشياء الآخرين فحسب
and steal it when you can't get it.
وسرقته عندما لا تستطيع الحصول عليها
As expected of you.
كما هو متوقع منك
Why aren't you
لماذا لا تقوم بتعليم ابنتك
educating your daughter at home?
تعليم ابنتك في المنزل؟
My little sister.
أختي الصغيرة
I haven't seen you in over a year
لم أرك منذ أكثر من عام
and the way you speak
وطريقة التحدث
is still so unflattering.
لا تزال ثابتة جدا
No wonder you don't even
لا عجب أنك لا
have the title of Princess Imperial
لقب الأميرة الإمبراطورية
at your age.
في عمرك
You...
أنت...
My little sister.
أختي الصغيرة
Are you getting mad at me again?
هل ستغضبين مني مجددًا؟
I remember that
أتذكر أنك
you were rejected by father
رفضك الأب
because you lost your temper with me
لأنك فقدت أعصابك معي
and he caught you
فأمسك بك
in a disgraceful manner.
بطريقة مشينة
Get out of here.
اخرج من هنا
Whenever I see you
كلما رأيتك
get mad at me
تغضب مني
and unable to do anything about it,
وغير قادر على فعل أي شيء حيال ذلك
I feel
أشعر
sorry for you.
أشعر بالأسف عليك
You...
أنت...
Mother.
أمي
Mother, are you all right?
أمي، هل أنت بخير؟
Are you...
هل أنت...
Princess Shun'an, are you all right?
الأميرة شونان، هل أنت بخير؟
I'm fine.
أنا بخير
Your Highness.
سموك
If you like this hairpin,
إذا كنت تحب دبوس الشعر هذا
just say it.
قل ما لديك فحسب
Princess Shun'an is a generous person.
الأميرة شون آن هي امرأة سخية
She'll definitely buy it for you.
ستشتريه لك بالتأكيد
Why would you
لماذا؟
hit her?
تضربها؟
You...
أنت...
You are sisters.
أنتن أختين
When did I hit her?
متى ضربتها؟
She didn't.
لم تضربها
Cry.
ابكي
- I didn't even move my hands. - Cry now.
- لم أتحرك يدي حتى - اسرعي الآن
She started it first.
بدأت الأمر أولا
Mother.
أمي
Mother, are you all right?
أمي، هل أنت بخير؟
Aunt.
عمّتي
My mother is your little sister.
أمي أختك الصغيرة
You are older than her.
أنت أكبر منها سنا
How could you hit her
كيف يمكن أن تضربها
when she was so tolerant of you?
في حين أنها كانت متسامحة معك؟
Nonsense!
هراء
When did I hurt your mother?
متى آذيت أمك؟
Jiamin.
جيامين
I know
أعرف
we are not welcome,
نحن لا نرحب به
but
ولكن
you can't just make things up.
لا يمكنك أن تختلق الأمور فحسب
You guys are too much.
أنتم أكثر من اللازم
Princess Shun'an.
الأميرة شون آن
Why don't you see a physician?
لماذا لا ترى طبيبا؟
I think it's swollen here.
أظن أن الأمر متورم هنا
Really?
حقًا؟
Mother.
أمي
I'll tell His Majesty.
سأخبر جلالة الملك
Jiamin.
جيامين
Bring it on.
أحضره
I'm not afraid.
لست خائفا
Your Majesty, please do me justice.
جلالتك، أرجوك اإقامة العدل
Mother has gone to rest,
لقد ذهبت أمي للراحة
and you are here making trouble.
وأنت هنا تثير المشاكل
So, what's wrong now?
ما الخطب الآن؟
Brother.
أخ
They made things up.
لقد تخلوا عن الأشياء
I have a witness.
لدي شاهد
Bring the guard here.
أحضر الحارس هنا
Greetings, Your Majesty.
تحياتي يا صاحب الجلالة
Let me ask you.
دعني أسألك
Did you see me hit her?
هل رأيتني أضربها؟
Your Majesty,
صاحبة الجلالة
no.
لا
Your Majesty.
جلالتك
Please do me justice.
من فضلك اإقامة العدل لي
He's your own servant.
إنه خادمك الخاص
Of course he's taking your side.
بالطبع إنه يقف في صفك
Your Majesty.
جلالتك
I have evidence.
لدي دليل
Look.
انظر
You...
أنت...
Please do me justice.
أرجوك أقضي عليّ العدالة
How dare you frame me!
كيف تجرؤ على تأطيري!
I will...
سوف...
Stop.
توقف
This is ridiculous.
هذا سخيف
Your Majesty.
جلالتك
I'm still grieving
ما زلت أشعر بالحزن
for Chan.
لتشان
That's why I was out of line.
لهذا السبب كنت خارج الخط
Please punish me.
أرجوك عاقبني
I have heard this
لقد سمعت هذا
countless times.
مرات لا حصر لها
Princess Hua.
الأميرة هوا
Yes, Your Majesty.
نعم، صاحب الجلالة
You were there.
أنت كنت هناك
What do you think?
ما رأيك
Your Majesty.
جلالتك
I believe that
أعتقد أن
Princess Le Yang
له
has her own reason.
لديها سبب خاص بها
That's justifiable.
هذا مبرر
So she does not need to be punished.
لذلك لا تحتاج إلى عقاب
Still, you can't let
مع ذلك، لا يمكنك السماح
Princess Shun'an
الأميرة شعنان
suffer for nothing.
تعاني من دون شيء
I think
أعتقد
you should step in
يجب أن تتدخل
to make amends to Princess Shun'an.
للتعويض عن الأميرة شون آن
Brother.
أخ
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
Shun'an.
تعال
You are not young anymore.
لم تعد صغيرا
I'll make you a Princess Imperial.
سأجعلك أميرة إمبراطورية
What do you think?
ما رأيك
- Thank you, Your Majesty.
- شكرًا لك يا صاحب الجلالة - شكرا لك يا صاحب الجلالة
(Hua Liuli again.)
(هوا ليولي مرة أخرى)
Thank you for today.
شكرا لك على هذا اليوم
Thank you.
شكرًا لك
Don't mention it.
عفوا
My mother's wish
أمنية أمي
was to become the Princess Imperial
كانت أن تصبح الأميرة الإمبراطورية
and now she has finally gotten her wish.
والآن حصلت على أمنيتها أخيرا
It all thanks to you.
كل ذلك بفضلك
Princess Jiamin.
الأميرة جيامين
You misunderstood.
لقد أسأت الفهم
I didn't do anything.
أنا لم أفعل أي شيء
Fine.
حسنا
Go ahead and pretend.
لا بأس، وتظاهري
How did you make my mother's cheek
كيف جعلت مبتذل أمي يحلم
so red?
أحمر هكذا؟
Yes.
نعم
Will it fade?
هل سيتلاشى؟
It's a blush.
إنه نعمة
Blush?
أحمق؟
By the way,
بالمناسبة
is it because they offended you
هل هذا لأنهم أسأت إليك
that you took action?
أنك اتخذت إجراء؟
Am I that much of
هل أنا إلى هذا الحد من
a grudge-holder?
الحائز على عطلة؟
Minmin.
مين
Liuli was doing justice.
كانت ليولي تحقق العدالة
You should learn from her.
يجب أن تتعلم منها
Let's go
لنذهب
and eat something delicious.
لتناول شيء لذيذ
I can't believe His Majesty.
لا أستطيع أن أصدق جلالة الملك
How could he make her the Princess Imperial?
كيف يمكنه أن يجعلها الأميرة الإمبراطورية؟
I'm so pissed off.
أنا منزعجة جدا
She'll cook for you.
سوف تطبخ من أجلك
Hua Liuli, stop right there.
هوا ليولي، قف في هناك
Stop pretending.
توقف عن التظاهر
Xie Yao.
شي ياو
Why are you being so harsh?
لماذا تتصرف بقسوة شديدة؟
You were not like this before.
لم تكوني هكذا من قبل
Listen.
استمع
His Highness
سموه
will marry me.
سوف يتزوجني
I am the daughter of a princess.
أنا ابنة أميرة
I will soon be crowned Crown Princess.
سأتوج قريبا أميرة للتاج
My father
والدي
is also the head of the Southern Civil Service.
هو أيضا رئيس الخدمة المدنية الجنوبية
Your family has resigned.
لقد استقالت عائلتك
His Majesty is not pleased.
جلالة الإمبراطور غير سعيد
Your glory is on the wane.
مجدك في انحدار
His Highness will definitely
سموه بالتأكيد
make the right choice.
اتخذ القرار الصحيح
Don't listen to her nonsense.
لا تصغي إلى هراء
We all know that the Hua family
كلنا نعرف أن عائلة هوا
has been loyal for generations.
كانت مخلصة لأجيال
My father also said that
وقال والدي أيضا
His Majesty will reinstate General Hua.
سيعيد الإمبراطور الجنرال هوا
Yes.
نعم
I can testify to this.
أستطيع أن أشهد على هذا
Thank you, Princess Shun'an
شكرا لك، الأميرة شعنان
and Jiamin.
وجيمين
You are so kind.
أنت لطيفة جدا
Xie Yao.
شي ياو
What are you
من أنت
trying to do with all this talk?
هل تحاول فعل كل هذا الحديث؟
If you're just trying to make
إذا كنت تحاول فقط الإدلاء
a harsh statement,
بيان قاس
then don't waste your time.
إذن لا تضيع وقتك
I misread you.
أنا أخطأت في قراءتك
You...
أنت...
Hua Liuli, shut up!
هوا ليولي، اصمت!
Aren't you afraid that
ألست خائفا من أنه
when His Highness comes,
عندما يأتي سموه
you won't even have time to pretend
لن يكون لديك الوقت حتى للتظاهر
before His Highness sees your true colour?
قبل سموه يرى لونها الحقيقي؟
Aren't you pretending too?
ألا تتظاهر أيضًا؟
You got me wrong.
أسأت فهمي
I'm naturally beautiful
أنا جميلة بشكل طبيعي
and delicate.
ودقيقة
Why do I need to pretend?
لماذا عليّ أن أتظاهر؟
The decree is here.
المرسوم هنا
My mother and I have been bullied by you
لقد تنمر عليّ وأمي
since we arrived in the capital.
منذ وصولنا إلى العاصمة
You guys are too much.
أنتم أكثر من اللازم
Princess Hua, please receive the decree.
الأميرة هوا، يرجى استلام المرسوم
I accept the decree.
أقبل المرسوم
By order of His Majesty,
بأمر من جلالة الإمبراطور
the Hua family has achieved great success
عائلة هوا قد حققت حققت نجاحا كبيرا
and has been loyal for generations.
وكانت مخلصة لأجيال
Princess Hua has served the people
الأميرة هوا خدمت الشعب
with great dedication.
بتفاني كبير
Hence, she will be crowned Crown Princess,
ومن ثم، ستكون تتوج أميرة التاج
with the title of Fushou.
بلقب فيتشو
What title?
أي عنوان؟
Fushou.
فوتشو
Wishing you
تمني لك
a long and blessed life.
حياة طويلة ومباركة
Congratulations, Princess Fushou.
تهانينا، الأميرة فوشو
(That's an awful name.)
(هذا اسم فظيع)
I am grateful to His Majesty.
أنا ممتن لجلالة الإمبراطور
Long live the Emperor.
عاش الإمبراطور ألاف السنين
What is His Majesty's intention?
ما هي نية جلالة الإمبراطور؟
I asked him every day
طلبت منه كل يوم
to reward my daughter,
لمكافأة ابنتي
but he didn't.
لكنه لم يفعل
Instead, he actually rewarded
بدلا من ذلك، كافأ في الحقيقة
Wei Mingyue's daughter.
ابنة وي مينغيويه
Honey, please calm down.
عزيزي، اهدأ من فضلك
His Majesty has his own considerations.
لدى جلالة الإمبراطور اعتباراته الخاصة
What considerations could he have?
ما هي الاعتبارات التي يمكن أن يراها؟
He just wants to humiliate me.
إنه يريد إهانتي فحسب
He's humiliating me!
إنه يهين نفسي!
Honey.
عزيزي
The walls have ears.
الجدران لها آذان
It's your fault!
إنه خطأك!
Get out of here! Now!
اخرجي من هنا! الآن!
You're worthless, too.
أنت لا قيمة لك أيضًا
Your sister
أختك
would never embarrass me like this.
لن تحرجني أبدا هكذا
I know you have a grievance.
أعلم أن لديك مظلمة
I will order someone to send some scriptures.
سأطلب شخصا ما أرسل بعض الكتب المقدسة
You can read them
يمكنك أن تراها
to calm your mind and concentrate.
لتهدئة عقلك والتركيز
I knew you would say that.
عرفت أنك ستقول ذلك
I want you to kill them for me.
أريدك أن تقتلهم من أجلي
Kill them!
اقتلوهم!
Why did you say
لماذا قلت
such a treacherous thing?
مثل هذا الشيء الغبي؟
What are you pretending for?
لماذا تتظاهر بهذا؟
Aren't you keeping
ألا تحافظ على
assassins all along?
قاتل طوال الوقت؟
Go.
اذهب
Kill them for me.
اقتلهم من أجلي
Kill them.
اقتلوهم
I want them all dead!
أريدهم جميعا ميتا!
It's better not to know
من الأفضل عدم معرفة
what you shouldn't know.
ما يجب ألا تعرفه
And don't say
ولا تقل
what you shouldn't say.
ما لا ينبغي لك قوله
Do you hear me?
هل تسمعوني؟
Xie Linzhou, you...
شي لينتشو، أنت...
Honey.
عزيزي
The States Assembly is coming soon.
جمعية الولايات قادمة قريبا
Envoys from various states will come.
سيأتي مبعوثون من مختلف المقاطعات
It will be crowded.
سيكون مزدحمًا
You should stay home and not go out
يجب أن تبقي في المنزل وألا تخرج
for the time being.
في الوقت الحالي
And don't worry.
ولا تقلق
The Hua Family is in charge of the States Assembly.
عائلة هوا هي المسؤولة من جمعية الولايات
They have their own
لديها مشاكلها
problems to deal with.
المشاكل التي يجب التصدي لها
You should stay
يجب أن تبقى
and look after your mother, too.
والاعتناء بأمك أيضا
(Ceremonial Hall)
(قاعة الاحتفال)
Greetings, Minister Hua.
تحياتي، الوزير هوا
You are here.
أنت هنا
Please sit down.
يرجى الجلوس
Minister Hua.
الوزير هوا
You should take a break
يجب أن تأخذي استراحة
before attending to official duties.
قبل الذهاب إلى الواجبات الرسمية
You've been
هل كنت
working too hard these past few days.
في هذه الأيام القليلة الماضية
The States Assembly is a big event.
جمعية الولايات حدث كبير
We can't afford any mistakes.
لا يمكننا تحمل أي أخطاء
Minister Zhang.
الوزير تشانغ
Anything happened today?
أي شيء حدث اليوم؟
The envoys of the Dianzhu are vegetarian.
مبعوثي الديانزو عالم نباتي
I have replaced
لقد حلت محل
all their meals and provisions
جميع وجباتهم وتوفير الطعام لهم
with vegetarian dishes.
بالأطباق النباتية
The Mosi envoys were not happy
لم يكن مبعوثي موسي سعيدين
when a citizen
عندما يكون المواطن
gave them the thumbs up
أعطهم الإثم
while they were strolling around.
بينما كانت تتجول
We have sent people to reassure them
لقد أرسلنا أشخاصا لطمأنتهم
and explain to them as you instructed.
والشرح لهم كما تعلمين
Thank you.
شكرا لك
Minister Hua.
الوزير هوا
And one more thing.
بشيء آخر
I don't know if it's significant.
لا أعرف إن كان ذلك مهمًا
Tell me.
قل لي
The Jinpo envoys
مبعوثي جينبو
have not yet arrived.
لم يصلوا بعد
The main focus of this assembly
التركيز الرئيسي لهذه الجمعية
is the negotiations to end the war
هو المفاوضات لإنهاء الحرب
with Jinpo.
مع جينبو
There is still
ما زالت هناك
no news from them.
لا يوجد أخبار عنهم
Who will Jinpo send this time?
من سيرسل جينبو هذه المرة؟
I was told that
قيل لي
it was He Yuanting, the second prince of Jinpo.
كان يوان تينغ الأمير الثاني من جينبو
He Yuanting
هو يوانتينغ
was a strong contender
كان منافسا قويا
for the Crown Prince's throne.
من أجل عرش ولي عهد
Somehow he lost his favour
بطريقة ما فقد صالحه
and disappeared from Jinpo
واختفى من جينبو
for a while.
لفترة من الوقت
Jinpo doesn't seem to be
يبدو أن جينبو لا
taking our negotiations very seriously
على محمل الجد الشديد
by sending him this time.
عن طريق إرساله هذه المرة
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
He will definitely come.
سيأتي بالتأكيد
We have to get ready.
علينا أن نستعد
(Pretentious Hour)
"ساعة التظاهر"
Minmin.
مين
Look, a new storybook.
انظري، قصة جديدة
Where did you get this ugly doll from?
من أين حصلت على هذه الدمية القبيحة؟
It looks like Prince Ying.
يبدو مثل الأمير ينغ
Let's go to Jinling Garden
دعنا نذهب إلى حديقة جينلينغ
and see Yun Han.
ويرى يون هان
But he doesn't
لكنه لا
show up much these days.
يظهر الكثير هذه الأيام
Shall I go to see the Crown Prince?
هل أذهب لرؤية ولي عهد؟
Don't mention His Highness
لا تذكر سموه
or Yun Han.
أو يون هان
I warn you.
أنا أحذرك
If you mention Prince Ying again, I will...
إذا أشارت الأمير ينغ مرة أخرى، سوف...
Fine.
حسنا
Is it my eyes problem
هل هي مشكلة عيني
or your eyes problem?
أم مشكلة عينيك؟
I don't know if your eyes
لا أعرف إن كانت عيناك
are good or not.
جيدة أم لا
Anyway, I only have eyes for...
على أي حال لدي عيون فقط
♪A new song is played by my fingers♪
♪ أغنية جديدة يعزف بها أصابعي ♪
♪I can't talk or sleep under the moon♪
♪ لا أستطيع التحدث أو النوم تحت القمر ♪
♪I'm missing someone walking around the pavilion♪
♪ أفتقد شخصا ما أتجول حول الجناح ♪
♪I can hardly tell anyone♪
♪ لا أستطيع أن أقول لأي شخص ♪
♪Who will be in this mortal♪
♪ من سيكون في هذه الوفاة ♪
♪Know my heart and how I cry without showing anyone♪
♪ عرفت قلبي وأنت كيف أبكي دون إظهار أي شخص ♪
♪The memory has gone♪
♪ لقد اختفت الذاكرة ♪
♪Whose face is showing in my dream♪
♪ يظهر وجهي في حلمي ♪
♪How many times do I need to go through this♪
♪ كم مرة أحتاج إلى المرور بهذا ♪
♪Crying alone in front of the window♪
♪ الزواج وحده أمام النافذة ♪
♪Hearing the rain last night♪
♪ الاستماع إلى المطر ليلة أمس ♪
♪But my heart will not change♪
♪ لكن قلبي لن يتغير ♪
♪The clouds are being covered by the shadow of the moon♪
♪ الغيوم يتم تغطيتها في ظل القمر ♪
♪Who is rolling up the sleeve with the wind♪
♪ من يدمر النوم بالرياح ♪
♪Not worried about the grudges but for the ones not around♪
♪ لا تقلق بشأن الضغينة ولكن من لا حولها ♪
♪Telling my sorrowfulness in Fengyi Pavilion♪
♪ عزيمة في جناح فنغ يي ♪
♪But it's a shame a few autumns have passed♪
♪ لكنه من المؤسف لقد مرت بعض الأوهام ♪
♪It's hard to balance between the world and the one we love♪
♪ من الصعب التوازن بين العالم بين العالم الذي نحب ♪
♪The clouds are being covered by the shadow of the moon♪
♪ الغيوم يتم تغطيتها في ظل القمر ♪
♪I'm waiting while turning back♪
♪ أنا أنتظر بينما أعود ♪
♪I sighed as the old days are no longer here anymore♪
♪ شاهدت كالأيام الخوالي لم يعد هنا بعد الآن ♪
♪How many worries are there♪
♪ كم عدد الهموم هناك ♪
♪How many of us can grow old together♪
♪ كم الكثير منا يمكن أن يكبر في السن معا ♪
♪I wish you can have the world and the one you love♪
♪ أتمنى أن يكون لديك العالم العالم الذي تحبينه ♪